# **VLADIK KHONONOV**

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT, SPEAKER, BLOGGER, MENTOR

vladik@khononov.com +972-50-765-7534 @vladikk

#### Profile

I'm a software engineer with nearly 20 years of industry experience. During the years I worked for companies large and small, in roles ranging from Software Engineer to Chief Architect.

When away from work, I maintain an active media career as public speaker and blogger. I am speaking and writing on topics such as Microservices, Domain-Driven Design, and more. Alongside the media work, I have a keen professional interest in Distributed Systems, Software Architecture, and Software Design in general.

In the remaining time, I read lots of books, fly R/C aircrafts, and help troubled animals.

#### Skills

Software Architecture and Design

Domain-Driven Design, Microservices, CQRS, Event Sourcing, Distributed Systems Design, Event-Driven Architecture, SOA

**Cloud Computing** 

Amazon Web Services, Digital Ocean

Platforms and Programming Languages

.NET & .NET Core (C# & F#), Python, NodeJS (JavaScript, CoffeeScript, TypeScript), Swift

**Databases** 

PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, MSSQL, Redis, MongoDB, Redshift

**Development Methodologies** 

Test-Driven Development, Behavior-Driven Development

### Education

The Open University of Israel

Dual Major, Management and Computer Sciences, 2011 (with distinction)

## Experience

Invesus Group - Chief Architect (2017-Present)

In 2017 Internovus was merged with Invesus, and I was promoted to the Chief Architect position of the Invesus group (Internovus, Naxex). In addition to my duties at Internovus, at Invesus I'm in charge of mentoring and helping teams to migrate legacy codebases into a Microservices and AWS Cloud based solutions.

Internovus - Chief Architect (2011-Present)

Internovus is a large scale online advertising and marketing company. As the first employee of the company I was in charge of both strategic and tactical software design and architecture.

We embraced AWS Cloud and Domain-Driven Design from the company's day one. We also employed state of the art technologies and architectural styles, such as Microservices, Serverless Computing, Event Sourcing, CQRS, Event-Driven Architecture, polyglot persistence, machine learning, and others.

In addition to my engineering duties, I built and managed international RND teams, mentored junior software developers and architects, and am in charge of research and technical guidance for the company.

Malam Team - Senior Software Engineer (2005-2011)

Right after I demobilized from the army, I started working as a junior software engineer for one of Israel's largest outsourcing companies - Malam. I worked on numerous strategic projects for MSN, Cellcom, Coca Cola, Keshet, and other companies.

Israel Air Force - Software and IT Engineer (2001-2005)

During my army service I served as an IT manager for the Human Resources department. I was in charge of building and maintaining information management systems (Magic, MS Access), administrating databases, and supporting the department's hardware.

During the service I was honored as an outstanding soldier.

Beit Tochna Ve Makhshev - Web Developer (2000-2001)

During my high school years I worked as a web developer for a small chain of computer stores.

I was in charge of building websites for local shops and small businesses.

Blog	<u>vladikk.com</u>
Recent Personal Projects	Design Heuristics for Service Boundaries  7 Years of Domain-Driven Design (Book)
Public Speaking	Bounded Contexts, Microservices, and Everything in Between (DDDx)  7 Years of Domain-Driven Design (Code Europe)  Full Speaking Profile
Publications	Devops: Exploring the Value of Microblogging, Cutter IT, Jan 2012
Human Languages	English - Fluent Hebrew - Fluent

 $Vladik\ Khononov - \underline{vladik@khononov.com} - +972-50-765-7534$ 

Russian - Mother tongue